<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Wei Liu&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Wei Liu&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 13:43:42 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blog5 - LAMP Stacks on Ubuntu</title>
      <link>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 13:43:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog5/</guid>
      <description>What is LAMP? LAMP (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP/Perl/Python) is an acronym denoting one of the most common solution stacks for many of the web&amp;rsquo;s most popular applications. However, LAMP now refers to a generic software stack model and its components are largely interchangeable Linux for operating system, Apache HTTP server, MySQL for the relational database management system and PHP/Perl/Python programming language. Install LAMP Stacks on Ubuntu  Update package for Ubuntu system Make sure to update the package repository cache to ensure it installs the latest versions of the software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog4 - Applcation deployment --ansible and dockerfile</title>
      <link>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 18:20:21 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog4/</guid>
      <description>Two ways to deploy applications to client side for supporting users Ansible   Ansible is Simpel IT Automation Ansible is an open source IT automation engine that automates provisioning, configuration management, application deployment, orchestration, and many other IT processes.
Playbook is the main thing of ansible. An Ansible playbook is an organized unit of scripts that defines work for a server configuration managed by the automation tool Ansible. Ansible plays are written in YAML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog3 - Docker intereview extension</title>
      <link>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Oct 2021 15:22:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog3/</guid>
      <description>Docker related interview questions:  Explain what happends when an SRE executes the following command:  docker run --name inclass hello-world  docker run = run the command in a new container and build all intermediate image as needed. &amp;ndash;name = Assign a name to the container which is &amp;ldquo;inclass&amp;rdquo; hello-world = the image to be used -p 9090:9090 = map local port 9090 to port 9090 inside the container -it = Container should have interactive terminal /bin/bash = run the bash command when the container is built   Explain what happens when a user types following into their browser:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog2 - Docker Start</title>
      <link>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 23:54:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog2/</guid>
      <description>Blog 2 Docker start What is Docker? Docker is a set of platform as a service (PaaS) products that use OS-level virtualization to deliver software in packages called containers. Containers are isolated from one another and bundle their own software, libraries and configuration files; they can communicate with each other through well-defined channels. Because all of the containers share the services of a single operating system kernel, they use fewer resources than virtual machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog1 - Markdown Syntax and Jump Proxy Note</title>
      <link>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 15:30:49 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog1/</guid>
      <description>Bog 1 Markdown Syntax and Jump Proxy Note Markdown cheatsheet 1. Paragraphs  Each line end with two or more spaces will cause skip line.  2. Headers,   Uses 1-6 hash characters (#) at the start of the line, corresponding to - .
This is Header H2 with (##) This is Header H3 with (###) This is Header H5 with (#####)   User “Underlined” using equal signs (=) as and dashes (-) as in any number.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog0 - Hugo starts</title>
      <link>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2021 00:38:13 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://liuwei0915.github.io/post/blog0/</guid>
      <description>Blog 0 Hugo starts what is the Hugo? Hugo is a fast and modern static site generator written in Go, and designed to make website creation fun again. Hugo is a general-purpose website framework. Technically speaking, Hugo is a static site generator. Unlike systems that dynamically build a page with each visitor request, Hugo builds pages when you create or update your content. Since websites are viewed far more often than they are edited, Hugo is designed to provide an optimal viewing experience for your websitebs end users and an ideal writing experience for website authors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
